Okay, so today we will finish the Greeks by discussing Aristotle.
好的，今天我们来完成对希腊的讨论，先说一说亚里士多。
And a lot of what I will say today will be controversial.
接下来我会说的那几句，能说得很久。
So feel free to challenge me.
其后再来回顾?
Feel free to ask for clarification.
好，先说一说亚里士多
Feel free to ask any questions.
好吧！先给我点儿…???????????????????????????????????????????????????????
So here's my argument.
...????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????
Aristotle is a paradox.
亚里士多是个悖论。
He is one of the mysterious figures in world history.
他是世界历史中的一位神秘人物。
He's one of the most famous, but he's one of the most mysterious.
他是个很久的…
He's a paradox for three reasons, okay?
他是三种原因的悖论，先说…
The first reason is he is considered
...????…??…???
to be one of the greatest philosophers in human history.
...??…???
He's next to Plato. He's certainly as influential as Plato.
他紧随柏拉托，确实与柏拉托同样有影响力。
But what is unique about him is we do not have anything,
但他那点儿………??…??…??
originally written by him, okay?
We have no text that
我们有一段文字...
we believe was personally written by him.
...
And that's unique in human history, okay?
We say Shakespeare was a great writer and
...
we can prove it or show it by reading his text.
We believe Aristotle is a great thinker,
...
a great writer, but we have no evidence,
a great...??...??...??
no text, to show us this is the case.
...??...???
We believe so, okay?
...??..??...??
So this is the first paradox.
...???????..??..???..??..???
The second paradox of Aristotle.
...??..??..??..??..???..??..???
Second paradox of Aristotle is he was a very prolific writer
...??..??..??..??..?????..??..???
and thinker. In fact, we believe he,
and thinker. Infact, we believe he,
there's about 200 works attributed to Aristotle.
}]
What is unique about his work
...????????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..???..??..??..??..??..??..???..??..译????????..??..?????????..??..?????..??..??..??..??..????????..??..??..?????..??..????????..??..?????..??..??..??..??????????..??..??????..?????..??..???????..??????..??..??????..??..????????..??..??????..??1????????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..?????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??
is the range of his thinking and his research.
...
So he's written a book on politics,
...??..??..??..??..??..??..??..???
right? What is the best political system?
...??..??..??…
He's written a book on poetics,
...
theater, basically. What makes for a good tragedy?
He's written a book on ethics.
他写了一本关于伦理学的书
What is a good life? What makes a good person?
...
He's written a book on rhetoric.
We have to..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..
How do you convince the audience that you are correct?
你怎么让观众相信你是对的？
He's also written books on physics.
他也写过关于物理的书。
He's written books on metaphysics.
他写了关于形而学的书
He's written books on physics.
他写了关于物理的书
He's written books on biology.
他写了关于生物学的书。
Okay? The range is just incredible.
好的？范围真是太棒了。
We have no analog in human history like him.
我们在历史上没有类似他的人。
He's simply unique in the range of his curiosity.
他在好奇心范围里很简单的没得有。”
Second paradox. The third paradox is most problematic.
第二个悖论。第三个悖论最为棘手。
We know that Aristotle studied under Plato for 20 years.
我们知道阿里士多·帕特里奥斯在十里程里里程里里程里里程里里程里里程里里程里里程里里
And so we also believe that Aristotle studied under Plato for 20 years.
和我们一起，...
Aristotle was Plato's most famous student.
...
The paradox is Aristotle's understanding
第51句：阿里士多的理解
of the universe is radically
第52句：是...
opposed to Plato's understanding of the universe.
第53句：...
Okay? And that's, again, is unique in human history.
好的？再一次，...
You would think the best student would carry on the master's work or at least build on it,
?
right? But Aristotle,
his understanding of the universe,
...
is in conflict with Plato's work.
In fact, you could also argue that
...
Aristotle is negating Plato's worldview.
Aristotle ... ...
Okay? So let me explain how.
好的？现在，让我来解释一下。
So we know Plato. We know that for Plato,
好的，先说一下吧。
there is a god, and it's called the form of the good.
有一位神，叫作“善的形式”
And the form of the good is what is the best.
“善的形式”是最好的。”
It's eternal, perfect,
它是永恒的，完美的，
and immutable.
且是不变的。
Okay? Now,
好的，先说吧！
the form of the good emanates other perfections.
好的，先说一…
What he calls the form of the ideal.
他所称的理想形式。
Okay? So these are concepts like justice and beauty and reason.
好的，先说吧！
And then these concepts manifest themselves
...
in forms like horse,
right? Or a woman.
对吗？或者是个女人。
Okay? And these are like the ideal, perfect,
好的，先说吧！
immutable, eternal manifestations.
不变的，永恒的表现。
Okay? So there's only one horse. It's up in heaven.
好的？所以只有一匹马。它在天上。
Everything else is a copy of this horse or imitation of this horse.
一切其它都是这匹马的复制品或模仿。
Okay? So we live in a shadow realm.
好的？我们住在影子世界里。
Okay? A shadow realm where everything is imitation.
好的？影子里一切都是模仿。
Okay? This is our reality. It's a shadow reality.
好的？这是我们的一切。
And that's why art and poetry and theater are so important.
和……好吧，...
And that's why music and theater are so bad. Because
...
they are really an imitation of an imitation.
Okay? So this is Plato's hierarchy.
好的？这就是柏拉图的层级。
So from this hierarchy and
好的，柏拉图的层级从此开始。
this world view, we can make certain extrapolations.
好的，柏拉古里…
Okay? The first extrapolation is for Plato,
好的？第一条推测是为柏拉图的
what is good is if you approach or
好的，先前…
return to the form of the good.
好的…
What is evil?
什么是好？
What is bad is if you move away from the form of the good.
什么是好，先前…
Okay? Right?
好的…
So poetry is evil. Mathematics is good.
...
Okay? Now, why is mathematics good?
Because mathematics is what allows
...
you to approach the
你去接近
form of the good.
形状的好事物。
All right? So let me give you an example of this.
全部好！让我来给你举个例子。
Okay? Let's say there's a circle.
好的？让我们说有一个圆圈。
Right? What Plato argues is no matter how hard you try,
好的，回到本地！
you could never,
好的，回到……
ever draw a circle in this world.
在这世界里画过圆圈吗？
Okay? Because a circle has an edge.
好的，圆圈有边。
So it's like literally impossible for you to create something without an edge.
于是就像是个圆圈有边的样子。
Right? You're like, well, I can draw on the computer.
好的，...
But if you go at a microscopic level, you will always find an edge.
...
Okay? So how do you create a circle?
Well, you create a circle by imagining it in your head.
...
Okay? So you draw a circle.
So what you're really doing is you're imagining the circle
...
because you're accessing the realm of the forms.
因为你正在进入形式的领域。
You're approaching from the good.
你正从善的角度来接近。
Okay? So it's only pure,
好的，...
it is only through a process of pure thought,
它只通过纯思维的过程，
pure philosophy, pure mathematics that
纯粘哲学，纯粘数学，方可开始理解这世界。
you can actually start to understand this world.
All right? That's Plato's understanding of the world.
全部好？那是柏拉图对世界的理解。
Aristotle has a completely different understanding.
亚里士多德有着完全不同的理解。
Okay? So Aristotle starts with this.
好的，先前的那句…
That God's a prime mover.
那是个神的首要动因。
Okay? So the prime mover, just imagine a big bag.
好的，先前…
Right? Something explodes.
...
Boom. It moves.
Boom. 它移动。
And it forces other things to move as well.
它又能让其他物体也移动。
So what Aristotle is saying is everything is really in motion.
所以，亚里士多德说的就是一切都在运动中。
Okay? Everything is change.
...
Because it was all caused by the prime mover.
And in Plato's, sorry, in Aristotle's world,
...
what is good is the good.
什么是好的就是好事
But what he's saying is if the thing that changes moves towards its purpose.
但方才方才方才...
Okay? Or the word he uses is called telos.
??
Telos. Okay?
Telos。好吗？
If you're moving towards your purpose, you are doing good in this world.
如果你朝着自己的目标前进，你在这个世界里就是好事。
If you're moving away from your purpose, you're doing bad in this world.
如果你离开了自己的目标，才是好事。”
Okay? So the example is a soldier. The purpose of a soldier is to fight and win wars.
好的？例子是个士兵。士兵的目的就是要去战斗并战胜。
So if you go fight and you do your best, you're doing good.
如果你去战斗，且做最好的表现，士兵士兵??
But if you run away from a war, you're doing bad.
…
you're doing bad, okay?
你们...??
So this is Aristotle's worldview
...??
and as you can understand,
as you can see,
如你所见，
these two worldviews cannot harmonize.
这两种世界观无法统一。
They are in conflict with each other.
它们相互冲突。
You have either one or the other, okay?
你们有两种选择，好的？
So let me highlight the three major differences between these two worldviews,
让我们来回顾一下这两种世界观的三大差异点！
okay?
...
And again, I need to emphasize this.
又一次，我要强调这一点。
I am not an expert on Aristotle.
我不是亚里士多德的专家。
I'm not an expert on Plato, okay?
我也不懂得很熟练的说法。
So I am committing oversimplifications.
我正在做出两种翻译”
Scholars who are experts will hear this and be outraged, okay?
But for the purpose of this class,
I feel these oversimplifications provide clarity, okay?
我觉得这些简化能给我方位吗？
Alright, so the first oversimplification is Plato is what we call a rationalist.
好吧，先前两句…
Aristotle is what we call an empiricist, alright?
Aristotle...
So these are two big words, but
So these are twobig words, but
the rationalist is just someone who believes that
...
you can access the truth through pure thought, okay?
Mathematics. An empiricist is someone who
...
believes you can only access the truth through observation
believes you can only accessthe truth through observation
and what we call induction,
and what we callinduction,
okay? Inductive logic, alright?
好的
So if I see a woman wearing a dress
...
and I see a woman wearing a dress, and a third,
I'm like, okay,
...
well from this I can logically deduce or induce
that all women wear dresses and that's what separates women from men, okay?
那所有的女子都穿着裙子，这就是把女子与男子分开的那一项。
So for Aristotle to seek the truth,
...
you have to observe and you have to induce, okay?
你需要观察并推断，好的？
So that's the first major difference.
那就是第一大差异
Second major difference is Plato is what we call a dualist.
第二个主要差异是柏拉图是我们所说的二元论者。
And I'm going to give you a little bit of a background on that.
第二个差异…
Aristotle is what we call a materialist.
阿里士多德是我们所说的物质主义者。
A dualist is someone who believes that there's a body and a soul, okay?
一个二元论者是指某人相信有身体与灵魂，才好。”
And if you believe there's a body and a soul,
如果你相信有身体与灵魂，则你也会认为灵魂更重要，因为灵魂是永恒的，身体会衰亡。
you also believe the soul is more important because
如果...
the soul is eternal, whereas the body will decay and die.
...
Aristotle, he's a materialist, so
阿里士多德是个物质主义者，所以他关注的是身体和身体的变化，不管有无灵魂。
for him the focus is on the body and what happens to the body, okay?
他关注的是身体和身体的变化，不管有无灵魂。
There may be a soul, there may not be a soul, he doesn't really care.
??
For him it doesn't really matter. What matters is what happens to the body, okay?
对他来说，没什么能算作可变的。只要有个身体就能算作可变的，~??~
The third major difference is Plato believes in the idea of a mutability,
...???????????
okay, or a call eternity.
???????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????
For Aristotle, almost nothing is a mutable.
对阿里士多德来说，几乎一切都是可变的。
Most things are a mutable, okay?
大多数事物都是可变的，好的？
The only thing that's a really a mutable is really God, but everything else is mutable.
唯一的那一件事物是神，才是可变的，才…
It will change over time. And so, for Aristotle,
它会随时间变化。于是，阿里士多德的概念是无穷。
the concept is infinity.
概念是无限的。”】}We need to translate cues 187-189. Provide array of three translations. Ensure Chinese natural. Use preferred terms. Let's translate: cue 187:
Things will always change, things will always move, there's no stopping movement.
? Actually cue 187:
But for Plato, things are eternal,
但对柏拉图来说，事物是永恒的，
there's a grand design,
有一个宏大的设计，
and nothing that changes really matters.
而且没有什么变化才算重要。
It doesn't really affect the grand design.
它并不真正影响宏大设计。
So for him, it's eternity.
于是，对他而言，就是永恒。
So these are the three major differences between Plato and Aristotle.
于是，这就是柏拉图与阿里士多德之间的三大差异。
Now what's really interesting for us is this conflict between Plato
现在，真正让我们感兴趣的是这场与柏拉图的冲突
and Aristotle is what will inform the philosophical debate for all of Western civilization.
而且在此后，给了给我方的哲学思路， 只给了…
So there are two major camps in Western philosophy.
??
There is the rationalist camp,
有理性派，
so people like Descartes, and then there are the empiricists, so people like David Hume.
…
And for most of Western history,
philosophers like Descartes will go back and forth between these two extremes, either the
哲学家如德卡特会在这两种极端之间来回去，…
Platonic ideal or the Aristotle reality.
…
Does that make sense? Is this clear?
Any questions? Sure,
...
go ahead. Yeah, so that's a great question.
And for Plato, okay, what we,
...
like our lives, the reality we live in is not real.
像我们的生活，所处的现实并非真实。
It's ephemeral. Whereas the form of the good, that's what's concrete.
它是短暂的，若是“好”之形态，才是“好”。”
That's what's eternal, okay?
其后期…
So I mean, like, I understand that's counterintuitive to us,
所以我想，像是我明白这点很久…
but the reason why it's kind of counterintuitive to us is because we're mainly influenced by Aristotle, right?
...
We live, we are materialist, right?
Science is materialistic.
...
But back then, and I would say back
then in Plato's time, and for most of human history,
...
it was assumed that
它被认为是…
our world was transitory,
它们…
or transient, or ephemeral, okay?
或短暂的，或短暂的，好的？
And it was a spirit world, okay?
又是一个精神世界？
That was real. And that was eternal.
那是实在的，且是永恒的。
Does that make sense?
那句 …
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, I think so.
是的，是的，好的。是的，我觉得是这样。
Okay. Okay. Again, this is oversimplification, okay?
好的，好的。再一次，…
Like, if you go to a scholar who understands itself,
像…如果你去找一位懂得自我者，
I will probably, he'll probably criticize me, okay?
我会去…
But I'm saying that for the purpose of this class, and for our understanding of Western civilization,
但我说的是，为了这门课的目的，以及我们对西方文明的理解，这就足够了。
this will do, okay? Just understand there's a major conflict between Plato and Aristotle.
这只是为了说明柏拉图与亚里士多德之间的主要冲突。
This will go on for thousands of years.
这将持续数千年。
This will inform the debate in Western civilization, okay?
这将为西方文明的讨论提供信息。
This is the fundamental debate in Western philosophy.
这就是西方哲学的基本论点。
All right? So let's go back to, let's summarize where we are.
好的？那我们回到，先把我们现在的进度总结一下。
Aristotle is a paradox, right?
亚里士多德是个奇异之谜，算吧？
We have nothing that he wrote originally.
我们没有他写过的原稿。
The range of his work is just incredible.
他的工作范围真是不可思议的。
It's unique in human history.
它在先前的古人类人类历史里有独特之处。
And then lastly, even though
又在此后又有…………??
we know Aristotle sat under Plato for like 20 years, at least,
我们知道亚里士多德在帕洛特里坐下了大约20年，至少
Aristotle came up with a very different
亚里士多德先后有个很大??
conceptualization of the universe. In fact, it is indirect.
其后又…
It's an indirect conflict with Plato's understanding, okay?
它是与帕洛特里理解的间接冲突，好吗？
So how is this possible? How are these paradox,
它的...??
how can we resolve these paradoxes?
??
Okay, so I'm gonna make an argument.
好的，我要做一个论点。
And I will slowly make this argument, but it is a controversial argument, okay?
我会慢慢地做这点，算是个别名？
My argument is that Aristotle was not a philosopher.
其…
He was not a thinker.
他不是思想家。
He was not a writer. What he was ultimately,
他不是作家。 终究他是个编辑。
is what I refer to as a censor.
他是个…
Censor. You can also use words like synthesizer, okay?
Censor...
Or editor. Or systemizer, okay?
...
But basically, nothing that
he thought was original to him, but
他认为是他自己的原创，但
he decided what would be political convenient for the moment,
他决定了什么是当时政治上方便的事物，
okay? That's what we mean by censor.
好的？这就是我们所说的“编辑”
And it's my argument that, you know, I'm not a thinker.
...
But let me make my argument that we understand Aristotle's censor, then
these three paradoxes go away.
...
We can explain away these paradoxes.
All right, so let me make my argument.
...???????????????????????????????????????????
Okay, my first piece of evidence is,
...???????????????????..??..??..??..??..?????..??..??..??..??..?????..??????..??..??..??..??..?????..?????..??..?????..??...??..??..??..??..??..?????..??..??..??..??..?????..??..??..??..??..?????..??....??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..1????..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..??..
We need to compare and
...
contrast the life of Phippus Sacc and the Macedon and Aristotle.
对比亚历克里斯·萨克斯的生活与马德克斯·亚历克里斯的生活。”
And when you do that, Okay?
当你把它们放在一起时，
And you put their lives side by side
...
into a! interesting parallels emerge okay
???
so let's look at their lives very simple
...
aristotle he was born in year 384.
arist ...
philip ii was born in year 383.
菲利普二世于383年出生。
that's about the same age right
...
now philip ii he's a prince of masson his father is the king right
aristotle his father was the court
阿里士多的父亲是宫廷医生
physician to the king he was the king's personal doctor
阿里士多的父亲是宫廷医生到…
right so from these two pieces of information what can we guess about philip and aristotle
...
they grew up together right does that make sense
aristotle's father was the personal doctor the king philip was the son
阿里士多的父亲是宫廷医生，菲利普是王子。
of the king it would make sense they grew up together it would make sense to be educated together all right
阿里士多的前景…
second thing that's interesting is from 367 to 3 348 okay
...
aristotle went to athens to study in plato
now around the same time okay in the year 369 to 365
...
philip went to thebes to study military innovation under the best generals in greece all right
and here i would extrapolate and
...
say the teenagers they're going
to further their education right
...
and learn the best scientific and
]}We need to translate cue [285]
military innovations in order to bring back the mastodon and
...
this happens all the time right in the 1980s china sent its best
and brightest to america to study science okay
...
so we can also surmise that
even while they were away they were still in contact
在离开时仍保持联系
with each other all
在离开时与相互联系
right now in 359
翻译1
philip became regent or basically king and from
]}We need to translate cues [292] and [293] into Simplified Chinese. The cues: [292]
then on he started this massive military campaign to conquer all of greece
...??????????????????????????????????????????
now one thing that
]}We need to translate [294] and [294? Wait we have cues [294] and [295]. We need to translate them. Let's read them: [294] then on he started this massive… [295]now one thing that. We need to produce translations. Use Chinese. Let's produce two translations. Ensure each string may contain at most one newline. Let's produce:
was interesting about philip's conquest of greece was
...
that
the athenians didn't really oppose him okay
the athenians didn'treally oppose him okay
and this is one of the great mysteries historians struggle with why is it
...
that philip ii he's going around he's conquering all these places
that are in conflict with athens and
athens doesn't really resist all right
...
and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and
]}
athens and
...
athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and
athens and athens and athens and
...
athens and athens and
athens和athens和
athens and athens
athens和athens
and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and athens and to democracy,
第310条：...
and that's why we must oppose him.
第310条??
So we can surmise that
...
Philip was bribing these Athenians to support him, and that's why there's
翻译：...
so little Athenian resistance to Philip.
...
If that's the case, then who's the middleman?
Who's the person who's in contact with these Athenian aristocrats?
谁在与这位百花?
Aristotle, right? Why, because remember,
??
Aristotle was at the academy for 20 years.
Aristotle ...
The academy in Athens at that time is like Harvard, Oxford today, right?
It's where all the rich and powerful go to study.
它是所有富贵人去学习的地方。
So for 20 years,
它们在此处…
Aristotle was in contact and
阿里士多德与...
became friends with the most powerful individuals in Athens,
阿里士...
and that's why when Philip needed to negotiate with the Athenians,
当时，菲利普需要与雅典人谈判时，正好把阿里士多德派去。
it would make the most sense to send Aristotle.
当时…
Okay, does that make sense? And
好的，能这样理解吗？
then we know that Philip united Greece in 338,
然后我们知道菲利普在338年统一了希腊。
and then 335, three years later,
和随后335，三年后，
Aristotle started a new school in Athens,
Aristotle … ?? ????????????????????????????????????????
a competition academy called the Lyceum, okay?
一个叫“利休姆”之类的竞赛学院，好的？
So what is the purpose of the Lyceum?
一个叫“利休姆”…???????????????????????????????????????????????????????????
So that's what I will discuss next, but does that make sense?
}]
There are direct parallels between the lives of Aristotle and Philip.
有点儿…………???????????????????????????????
Okay? And we can guess or extrapolate or deduce
...
that Aristotle and Philip were very close throughout their lives,
阿里士多德与菲利普在一生中相互甚近，互相协助。
and they were helping each other.
阿里士多德与菲利普一生中相互相近，俩个都相互协助
Okay? Does that make sense?
OK? 先前? 先后??
Okay, so now the question then
OK
is, why was Philip going around conquering all of Greece?
...
Well, Philip had a vision for the world,
and it's something we call the Pan -Hellenic Project.
...
Okay, so a Pan -Hellenic Project.
OK
Alright, so at this time
and throughout most of its history,
翻译
Greece was divided into city states all around the world,
希腊被分成各个城邦，遍布世界各地，
mainly in mainland Greece, but
希腊在大陆地位于大陆地，
also across the aegean in Asia Minor, Anatolia, okay?
又跨亚德海，安塔利亚，OK?
Across all these different islands and
跨所有这些不同的岛屿
into North Africa and
到达北非，
across the Adriatic,
跨越亚德里亚海
also into Italy as well, okay?
...
So you have this sprawling Greek world.
And there were many who believed
...
that this Greek world should unite together
that this Greek worldshould unite together
because there's a common ancestry,
...
all right?
So it was a dream of many philosophers that
So it was a dream ofmany philosophers that
a great man of history would arise and
...
unite all of Greece by basically defeating Persia.
unite...
And Philip II said, hey, that's a great idea,
and it should be me, okay?
361: ... ???
But the problem is
?
the Pan -Atlantic Project
泛大西洋计划
assumes a common Greek identity, and it didn't really exist at that time.
In fact, Greeks probably had more power over the Greek people and
在此时，希腊人们很可能有更大…
more common with their local cultures than with each other, right?
...
So if you were a Greek living in Asia Minor,
如果你在亚细亚小?
you were probably more Persian than you were Greek,
...
okay?
好的？
So in other words,
在此时…
Philip needed someone, a censor basically,
翻译结果
to create a Greek identity,
right?
...
And the way you do that
And the way youdo that
is by taking all this vast universe
...
of knowledge that the Greeks created and
you create an encyclopedia or a series of textbooks
that define what it means to be Greek,
right?
对吗？
You standardize and you systemize Greek knowledge.
你把希腊知识标准化并系统化。
Does that make sense? And so
...
that's probably what Aristotle was doing when
he started the Lyceum.
他开始了吕凯姆学派。
He had lots of students, okay?
他有很多学生，好的！
So he was like a chief on the Greek, like standardizing the Greek and the Hebrew.
...
Yeah, so throughout history, all conquerors did this, okay?
Because that was the only, because by standardizing and systemizing knowledge
因为那是唯一的，因为标准化与统一知识而已。
was the best way for you to co -opt the elite
]}We need to translate cues 387 and 388. Provide JSON with translations array of two strings. Use Chinese terms. Let's translate: cue 387:
and to showcase your legitimacy, okay?
...
Otherwise, the intellectual elite would think of you as a barbarian conqueror,
all right? And the best way that
...
you co -opt the intellectual elite is by
???
showcasing a new systematic knowledge, okay?
]}We need to translate cue 393. Also? Wait earlier cues 387-388? Let's parse. The user says
Does that make sense? All right.
So, the problem is
...
that in 336,
???
Philip was assassinated and his son, Alexander,
菲利普去世，亚历山大继承王位。
came to a throne, came to the throne.
菲利普去世后，亚历。
And as we discussed last class,
...
Alexander had a very different vision from the Greek and the Greek,
and he wanted to become his father. His father wanted to unite the Greek world.
和...
Alexander wanted to conquer the entire world to show he was superior to his father,
??
okay? And unbelievably, incredibly,
好吧？ 这回 … ………………………………………………
he was able to do so,
他能在十几天里完成…
conquer most of the world in about 10 years' time.
...
So now, suddenly,
you have this sprawling empire all around the world, okay? So
我们来把这片广阔的帝国画出来吧。
let's just sketch out how vast this new empire was.
let's just sketch out howvast this new empire was.
Okay, so you have, you know, Greece and Macedon.
好的，先说一下，希腊和马其…
All right, okay? So that's the Greek homeland.
好的，先说…
Thank you. That's the Greek homeland, right?
...
But hey, over here, you have Anatolia.
This is Mesopotamia.
这是个...??
Over here is Afghanistan.
Oh, sorry, sorry, it should be Iran, sorry.
...
Iran, Afghanistan.
伊朗，阿富尼亚
And you also reach as far as Pakistan, okay?
...
And down here, you have the Levant,
在此处有拉维特?
and you have Egypt, all right?
??
This was not supposed to happen. Philip and the Panhellenic Project,
imagine like their conquest would extend up around here,
想象他们的征服会扩展到这里，
okay, because you're uniting the Greek world.
好的，正好把希腊世界统一起来。
Alexander went too far, and now you're,
亚历山大走得太远，现在你已征服了已知世界的大部分，OK吗？
you've conquered most of the known world, okay?
亚历山大去到很久?
Then Alexander died, and then
425. 之后，亚历山大去世后，...
the empire was divided into three major fragments.
425?
Over here, you have something called the Antigonid Empire,
在这里，你有一个叫做安提冈帝国的国家，
okay? The Antigonid Dynasty, okay?
安提冈王朝，
So that's one piece of the empire.
...
Down here, you have Ptolemy, okay?
Ptolemy was one of Alexander's general, and he took over Egypt.
帕托勒米是亚历山大将军之一，他接管了埃及。
And over here, you have something called the Seleucid Empire,
在此处有一个叫做塞勒乌德帝国的名字。
founded, of course, by the general Seleucus, okay?
塞勒乌德帝国由塞勒乌德将军起始，
And over here, you have other smaller kingdoms as well.
在此处还有其他小王国。
So you have this vast empire,
这就是大帝国，
and this is something that was unplanned and unexpected.
这是一种未预料的意外之事。
Now that you've conquered these places,
现在已征服这些地方，
your concern or your problem is, how do we conquer them?
现在的工作是：先后先后？
Govern, okay?
其后再去…
So you need a new culture.
在此处需要新文化。
And so these different generals adopted different strategies.
在此处，先后……
So for example, here,
]}We need to produce translations for cues [440], [441], [442]. Wehave previous translations for [440] maybe? Actually we have [440]
the Persian culture is extremely well established,
波斯波斯波斯…
and the Seleucid king
...
and his hearers decided a process of localization,
okay? Or another word we can use is synchronization.
...
Synchronization, okay?
同步化，好的？
Meaning two different religions or two different cultures come together
两种不同的宗教与…
and coalesce together, okay?
合并在一起，好的？
So throughout the Seleucid Empire, it was really a process of synchronization.
在整个塞尔维亚帝国里，...
The Greeks adapted themselves to local customs
译文1
and to local culture, okay?
译文2
At the same time, the Greeks were conquerors.
在同一时间，希腊人是征服者。
So they still needed to maintain a coherent identity, okay?
在同一时间…
So it made sense for them
它们采用了多种亚里士多德的作品，...
to adopt a lot of Aristotle's work.
...
Remember, Aristotle was creating a panhellenic identity
记得吧，亚里士多德…
and so he basically created a lot of textbooks,
记得…
he basically created a encyclopedia.
他基本上创建了一部百科全书。
So it made sense for them to import Aristotle's work.
于是他在此时刻把希腊人们的工作导入了。”
Also it's important and remember,
...
Aristotle was Macedonian
and
...
a a a along this time Greeks did not consider Macedonians to be Greek.
在此时刻…
This is why it's called the Pan -Hellenic project, not the Pan -Greek project.
在此…………………
Also Greeks were very condescending towards Macedonians
]}We need to output JSON with translations array of 3 strings for cues 464-466. Provide Chinese translations. Use line breaks if needed. Let's translate each cue. Cue 464:
because they saw Macedonians as barbarians. So
因为他们把马其人视为蛮族。于是……
it was in the best interest of these new
它在这些新马其人征服者的最佳利益中……
Macedonian conquerors to exaggerate or to highlight the intellectual contributions of Aristotle.
马其人征服者把亚里士多德的智力贡献夸大或突出……
Does that make sense? Ptolemy's Egypt was very different.
...】...
Egyptian culture has been around for thousands of years
...??…
and the Europeans are very proud of their culture.
...???
This is a problem because
翻译1
you're very proud of your local culture you don't like foreign rulers
翻译2
and this is something that
翻译1
the Persian Empire struggled with throughout the centuries that it passed.
...
The Persians dominated Egypt. The Persians were famous for their openness
翻译1
and tolerance. Basically you are allowed to practice your own religion
翻译2
and they're very supportive of that.
和他们很支持那件事。
The most famous example are the Jews, right?
最著名的例子是…
The Persians supported in rebuilding the Second Temple.
帕提亚人支持重建第二圣殿。
We'll get to the Jews later on.
我们会在后面再说帕提亚人。”
But because the Persians were so supportive of local culture in Egypt,
因为帕提亚人如此支持埃及当地文化，埃及人多次起义。
the Egyptians rebelled against Persia many many times.
因为帕提亚人很久…
So Ptolemy and
his hearers didn't want to make the same mistake.
他的听众们不想再犯同样的错误。
They wanted to impose a new culture
他们想把...
on the Egyptians in order to show
...
that they were superior
它们是更高的存在
and therefore more divine than Egyptians.
它们是更高...
So Ptolemy did many things that started this process.
于是，托勒密做了许多事，开启了这一过程。
The first thing that he did was he stole Alexander's body from Babylon.
他先把亚历山大之身从巴比伦取回，先后把它回到巴比伦。
Where he died and brought it back to Egypt.
他先把亚历山大…
Because Egyptians saw Alexander as a god, as a son of a god, right?
因为埃及人把亚历山大视为神，像神之子，才吧？
So to establish legitimacy in Egypt,
于是………………
Ptolemy went on a military expedition and
………………
stole the body of Alexander which
偷取亚历山大之身，随后引发了名为“多伊奥基之战”之事，随后又回到…
started something called the War of the Diochi,
...
basically the successor wars.
That's the first thing he did. The second thing that
那是他做的第一件事。第二件事是他建立了一个新的首都，叫亚历山大。
he did was he established a
那是他做的...??...?????
new capital in Alexandria called Alexandria.
?????
Ok? So this was mainly a Greek city.
好的？所以这主要是个希腊里…
It was a new Greek city founded by Alexander and
...
this is where they house Alexander's body.
The third thing that he did was he started to sponsor
第3件事是他开始赞助……
something called, we call today the Museion.
...
Ok? The Museion is the root of the English The Museion is the root of the English word museum.
But the museum was really the world's first research university.
...
So Ptolemy and
his hearers brought together the greatest
...
Greek scholars in the world to basically
希腓学者在世界上基本上继续亚里士多德的工作，以标准化并系统化希腓文化。
continue the work of Aristotle to standardize
希腓学者...
and systemize Greek culture so
...
that they can impose it on the local Egyptian culture.
它们可以把它强加到当地的埃及文化上。
Does that make sense? And
它能给我方块？
the most famous aspect of the museum is the Library of Exandria.
“可是………」
And Ptolemy spent a lot of money
帕托勒米花了不少钱
on the Library of Exandria,
在库尔特里亚图书馆
mainly by going around and collecting original manuscripts.
主要是去收集原稿
So a representative went to Athens.
...
And he went to the library of Exandria. And said,
他去到了库尔特里亚图书馆，随后说：
we at the Library of Exandria would like the original copies,
他在库尔特里亚图书馆里去了个别名
the original manuscripts for Aeschylus,
原稿给阿埃斯库尔斯，索福克勒斯和欧里庞斯，三位大作家。
Sophocles, and Euripides, the three great playwrights.
原稿给…
And the Athenians are like, we can't do that because they're like gods here, okay?
安第尼人说：我们没能做这事，因为他们是神啊，行吗？
We're not gonna give you original manuscripts.
我们不再给你原稿。”
And the Egyptians said,
all we're gonna do is we're gonna take these manuscripts back to the Library of Exandria
...
where our scribes will copy them out,
在此处…
okay? That's all we're gonna do.
...
And then we'll give it back to you.
And as a guarantee, we're gonna give you like 15 talents of silver, okay?
...
And that's like a billion dollars back then.
The Athenians have never seen so much money.
...
So Athenians will say, well, okay,
well, if it's just to spread Greek culture,
...
we can actually deal with that, okay?
我们可以处理这个，好的？
So we'll take the deposit, 15 talents, and we'll give you the manuscripts.
我们把把...
The Egyptians took the manuscripts, placed it in the Library of Exandria,
埃及人把手稿放进了埃克斯安德里亚图书馆，随后又把手稿放进了…
and said, hey, Athenians, keep the money, okay?
...
Because the Egyptians under Ptolemy were focused on turning the Library of Exandria
???
and Exandria into the intellectual capital of the Greek world,
all right?
好了？
And so what happened was that
可是…
after Alexander died and his generals took over,
亚历山大去世后，统帅们接手，随后…
the Panhellenic project really became what we call the Panhellenistic project.
...
Okay? It went from uniting the Greek world into spreading Greek culture all around the world.
好的？它从统一希腊世界扩展到全世界的希腊文化传播。
And that's why we have Greek culture still with us today,
而这就是…
okay, because of this process.
好的，…
So, let's go back to the Original Paradox, all right?
所以，让我们回到原始悖论，好的？
Why – there are three paradoxes, right?
为什么——有三种悖论，对吗？
The first paradox is why do we have nothing original from Aristotle?
第一个悖论是：我方…
The answer is because Aristotle didn't write anything original.
The answer is because Aristotledidn't write anything original.
He stole every fucking thing. thing from other thinkers and
他把所有东西都拿来用。
had his students copy it out in manuscript form.
他把…
It doesn't make sense. Second is why are his works
它不太好说。第二点是他的作品多么？
so diverse? Why is the range so great?
它不太好说…
The answer is because he was trying to capture the essence of Greek knowledge.
答案是因为他试图捕捉希腓知识的本质。
He was trying to unify Greek
他又能把…
knowledge into an encyclopedia for dissemination around the world.
将知识编成百科全书，传播到世界各地。
The third thing is, the most interesting thing is,
]}We need to translate cue [561] and [562] into Simplified Chinese. Thetranslation should be natural, consistent with terms. The cue [561] is
why is Aristotle's philosophy
为什么阿里士多夫人?
so different from Plato's worldview?
...
That's a really interesting question.
第 5 句...???
Why are they so different?
??
So let's switch our perspective and ask ourselves.
把...??
If you were king of Macedon, if you were Philip Alexander,
...
what's your problem with Plato's philosophy?
你对柏拉图哲学有什么问题？
You have a problem. What is it?
你有问题。是什么？
Any guesses? You're Alexander, you're Philip.
你猜了？你是亚历山大，菲利普。
You really hate Plato. Why? Why?
你真的很喜欢柏拉图吗？为什么？为什么？
Well, the problem with Plato is,
好吧，柏拉图的事情是...
you go to Plato, you're Alexander, you go to Plato and says, I want to conquer the world.
你去柏拉图，去到达里亚...
Right? Plato would say, what's the point?
对吧？柏拉图会说，是什么意义？
It's all not real, Alexander.
它全是没事儿的！亚历山大！
You're just wasting your time.
你只会去…
You can conquer the world, but all you're doing is conquer a shadow.
我可以去...??
What's real is the form of the good.
]}We need to translate cues 578-580. Provide JSON with translations array. Each string may contain newline. Use simplified Chinese. Let's translate: cue 578:
Right? Alexander, study mathematics,
? Wait actual cue: [578] You can conquer the world, but all you're doing is conquer a shadow. So translation:
man. Okay?
Do more math. Stop going around
做点数学吧！
and killing people.
...
Do more math. Right and
做点数学吧！
we know what Alexander would do here.
...
Alexander would probably cut off Plato's head.
亚历山大可能会砍下柏拉图的头。
Alexander and Philip hate this thing.
亚历山大和菲利普都讨好这件事。
This thing is idiotic.
这件事很傻。
I want to conquer the world, but this philosophy is telling me it's pointless.
我想征服世界，但这哲学说它是空的。
What matters is mathematics.
翻译1
What matters is a philosophy. philosophy. Now,
翻译2
let's now compare
让我们来比较一下
this with Aristotle's
prime mover theory.
翻译1
What Aristotle was saying is, everything is motion,
翻译2
and what is good is if you fulfill your purpose.
...
Now, if you're Alexander or Philip, this makes more sense.
I'm Philip, my purpose is to unite the Greek world,
I'm Philip, my purpose isto unite the Greek world,
and the more I unite,
和我越发统一，
the more good I'm doing for this world, right?
我方才算得好？
Also, if you're a king,
翻译1
you want your citizens,
翻译2
your soldiers, your workers to work hard, right?
你的士兵们，工人们都要努力工作，对吗？
Well, for Plato,
Well for the ...?? ?? ?????
working hard is just useless.
工作很忙只是无用的
You're imitating an imitation, right?
你正在把握手握手的握手握手？
When you create art.
当你创作艺术时。
But here,
当时…????????????????????????????????????????
working hard is what gives you purpose.
工作很忙就是给你目的的
It's what gives you happiness.
工作很忙给了我方块
Okay? So
好的？所以
Aristotle also promoted two major concepts.
亚里士多德也提出了两个主要概念。
The first is erite.
第一个是埃里特。
The second is eudaimonia.
第二个是eudaimonia。
Okay? Erite is just excellence.
好的？e‑里特就是…
Okay? Alexander has erite because he is an excellent general.
好的…
When you have erite and
当你拥有了e‑里特并且
you are achieving your purpose, then you achieve eudaimonia, okay?
当你在完成自己的工作，才会有…
Which is just flourishing or happiness.
当时…
And that's the purpose of life, to have erite and to achieve eudaimonia.
和……就是生活的目的，拥有e‑里特并且…
So work hard. Fight for Alexander.
...
Support him as he conquers the world.
Because he's making the world better.
因为他在做…
Okay? Does that make sense? I have a question about that.
...
So if I'm a soldier and
my purpose is to be a good soldier,
我的目的就是成为一名好士兵，
am I not approaching the form of the good that
]}We need to produce JSON with translations array of 3 strings for cues 626-628. Provide Chinese translations. Use line breaks if needed. Let's translate each cue. 626:
there's this ideal soldier out there and the closer I can get to
? Wait cue 626 is
that, the more engaged I am in the face of the world?
...
Okay, that's a great question. Yeah, thanks, Doug.
Okay. All right. So the question
...
then is, if I'm a soldier and
然后是：如果我是一名士兵，且…
I'm a soldier, and I'm, you know, working hard and
我…
winning battles, am I not approaching the form of the good?
赢得战斗，我是否正接近善的形态？
And the answer is, for Plato, it's not.
对了，答案是：对柏拉图而言，已是如此。
The reason why is, what do you do in this material world is pointless.
因为这片物质世界，才是…
Okay? Because this material world, it's not real.
OK?
So whatever you do is not real.
所以你所做的就是…
Does that make sense? Okay?
...
So what you need to do is return to the form of the good.
于是你需要回到善的形态。
But your body can't do that.
但…
Your soul can do that.
你的灵魂可以做到这一点。
So your use of the body is pointless.
于是，身体的使用就算是空中之举。
You have to use your soul.
你需要用灵魂
You have to use your mind. All right?
你需要用脑袋，嗯？
Therefore, you have to be a good person.
因此你要成为好人
Therefore, you have to engage in philosophy and mathematics.
Therefore, you have to engagein philosophy and mathematics.
And that's how you return to the form of the good.
你回到好事的形态。
Your use of the body,
...
you're just deluding yourself.
Okay? All right?
OK? 先前回?
And if you engage in art, you're just deluding yourself.
Then you are deluding others.
...
And that's more evil. If you're Alexander and you're conquering others
翻译
and forcing them to believe your fake philosophy, then you're committing the most evil in the world.
...
Does that make sense? All right?
All right. So, yeah.
好的，...
All right. So
好的。
this is my theory of how to best resolve the three paradoxes of Aristotle.
这是我关于如何最优解三种亚里士多德的悖论的理论。
Okay? Does that make sense? There's basically a censor who is working for Philip and Alexander.
好的，...
And he was trying to develop a pan
...
-Hellenistic identity in order to unite the world they conquer.
-希腊斯特里克身份以统一他们征服的世界。
Okay? So that's my argument.
-好的，算是这样吧。
Any questions about this overall argument?
任何问题吗？
Does it make sense to you guys? Okay?
好的，...
I've got a few questions.
我有几个问题。
Go ahead. Yeah. Thank you.
继续吧。好的。谢谢。
Go on. All right. Go ahead.
继续吧。好的。继续。
So one of the questions is how do you know you're going to.
于是，问题之一是：你怎么知道自己要做什么？
So I'm going to ask you a question. That's a good question.
我来问你一个问题。好吧，先说个好点的！
Yeah. Okay. All right.
好的，先说！
So how do we know he didn't write any of his works?
我想要先给你们说个咱们的…
Okay. The answer is this.
好的。答案就是这样。
When you write something,
当你写下去时，
you're actually manifesting your thought.
你正好在表现自己的想法。
Right? But your thought comes from your personality.
对吗？但你的想法来自你的个性。
So if you look at any work of genius,
所以如果你看任何天才的作品，
it's original and unique.
它是原创的且独一的。
Okay? Does that make sense? In other words, if you read Shakespeare, guess what?
好的？这有道理吗？换句话说，读《莎士比》时，猜什么？
There's no other Shakespeare in the world.
有别的《百里》？
If you're trying to imitate Shakespeare, you look like an idiot.
...
Okay? Homer is unique. Plato is unique.
好的？荷马是独一的。普罗塔是独一的。
There's no point in trying to imitate them.
有点儿好像去看他。 只要看点儿。
You can't do it because you are not them.
不必看点儿。
Okay? Now, when you look at Aristotle,
好的？现在看阿里士多德时，
there's something unique about Aristotle.
有点儿…………………
So, you know, when you read Plato, the Republic, there are certain ideas that stand out.
…
Like, how to go to the cave.
像这样去洞穴。
Right? There's certain phrases that capture your imagination.
对吗？有些短语能让你想起。
That doesn't exist with Aristotle's texts.
那不在阿里士多德的文本里。
Okay? They're written like textbooks. So
...
the argument for the longest time was
Aristotle did write his own books,
...
but they were lost to us. And
但它们已遗失。然后
his students had to reassemble his thinking from their own memory.
他的学生们要凭记忆重新拼凑他的思想。
Okay? So, yeah, that's how we know.
好的？于是这样就得知。
But this is generally agreed upon.
但这点已普遍认同。
We have nothing that Aristotle wrote.
我们没有阿里士多所写的东西。
Aristotle wrote originally. Okay?
阿里士多最初写作。
So maybe the follow -up question then
所以，接下来问题是
would be, is it possible
是的，能否
that his ideas were for the empire?
他想法的...
And they could have been co -opted by forces of that.
它们也可能被那股力量共同接管。
That's right.
没错。
And is that as much of a.
它们是那样的。
Is that.
是的。
Yeah. Okay. So thank you, Doug.
好的，感谢你，杜格。
Okay. Yeah. So, yeah.
好的，好的。
So, there are many different possibilities of how Aristotle can become
所以，亚里士多德可以成为……的多种可能性。
so influential. Okay? The first possibility is,
好吧，先前的那句“先前”…………………
as I argue, he was actually a partner of Philip's.
先前……………………??
That they were both trying to promote the pan -Hellenic project.
译文1
Okay? That's the first possibility.
译...
But then the possibility is, as Doug says,
?
he was just a philosopher.
他只是个哲学家。
He was a student of Plato's.
他是柏拉图的学生。
He was very smart. And he was a very good teacher.
他很聪明，且是个好老师。
And after Alexander and
718. 之后，亚历山大和
his generals conquered the world,
719. 其大将军们完成了…
they needed a symbol of Macedonian cultural superiority.
720. 归一…
And they just decided upon Aristotle because it was most convenient.
Right? So that's another possibility.
Right? So that'sanother possibility.
Okay?.
??
Just from the part there about Aristotle's.
只要从那段关于亚里士多德的部分开始。
I think that kind of sounds up to me.
我觉得那种声音对我很有启发。
I mean, I'm not sure.
我说，我不确定。
I'm not sure. But he rejected too much onto his dad.
我不确定。 但他把它放在了...
But his dad was a physician, right?
...
. That's right..
??
If that's your approach to the world,
如果你们...??
you are looking for much more materialistic.
...
If you're looking for.
如果你们...??
. Right?
...
. But you need much more.
Yep.
是的。
Yep, exactly.
是的，完全正确。
So, yeah, so it is entirely possible
that Aristotle was a materialist
because that was just his personality, right?
因为那只是他的个性，才好吗？
The influence from his father, who was a physician, okay?
因为那是个别的…
But that creates another problem, which is if you are
翻译成中文：
so opposed to Plato's understanding of the world,
? 1? 1? 1? {
right, because you're a materialist and he's a dualist, why were you studying under Plato for 20 years?
744: 右，因为…
Does that make sense?
...
Does that make sense? So that creates another problem.
译文1
All right, so another thing I want to point out is,
译句
okay, how we have Aristotle's works today,
好，像我们现在有亚里士多德的作品，
there are three different possibilities, okay?
好的，先前有三种不同的说法，先前…
The first possibility is that Aristotle,
?
in his lifetime, he organized his students and
在他的生前，...
created this encyclopedia, okay?
...
It's no different from professors at universities today, right?
Professors who are scientists, they actually do very little of that.
教授们是科学家，他们实际上做的很少。
They have the original research. They have the students do it.
他们有原始研究。他们让学生去做。
They're the ones who supervise the entire process, okay?
他们是负责整个过程的监督者。
So it's possible, that's the first possibility.
757. 于是可得如此，先前的那一条可是先前的那条…
Aristotle was supervising the work of creating a Greek identity.
?
The second possibility is after Aristotle died,
his students started to remember, recall
他的学生开始记住，回顾
his lectures. And that's why so much of his work is fragmentary, okay?
他的讲座…??…????????????????????????????????????????????????????
We don't have complete manuscripts. And the third possibility, okay? And it's a very important one.
??
The third possibility is Aristotle is a fiction
第三种可能是亚里士多德是由亚历山大图书馆的学者们创造的虚构人物
created by scholars at the Library of Alexandria,
由亚历山大图书馆的学者们把它合成了
okay? So it's really the scholars at the Library of Alexandria who created Aristotle.
...
And they did so by synthesizing all this work.
And then they gave it to, they accredited it to,
...??...???
attributed it to Aristotle in order to create the legend of this philosopher,
????????????????????????????????????????????
okay?
好的？
Does that make sense? Yeah.
那好吧！
Okay. So let's have an argument about Confucius.
好的。让我们来讨论一下孔子。
Let's have this discussion about Confucius, okay?
好的，先说点儿…
But I want to very quickly talk about the Greek legacy.
但我想快速谈谈希腊遗产。
Because even though we can argue back
因为…
and forth about Aristotle and
...
his providence, what is not debatable is the profound influence
that Aristotle had on the world, okay?
那位亚里士多德对世界产生的影响，好的？
We can argue if Aristotle was the original writer or the original thinker.
我们可以讨论亚里士多德是原始作家还是原始思考者。
But what is not debatable is the tremendous influence he had on the entire world,
但这点不容争议：他对全世界的影响巨大，
okay? So there are three aspects of the Greek legacy I want to discuss.
...
The first aspect is the Greeks created a new way of being human,
第一点是希腊人创造了一种全新的“人类”观念，“好吧！”，“可见”。”】}We need to translate cues 781-783. Provide translations array with 3 strings. Ensure Chinese natural. Use line breaks. Let's craft. 781:
all right?
. Actually cue:
So let's look at the major thinkers.
. Wait: [781] The first aspect is the Greeks created a new way of being human, [782] allright? [783] So let's look at the major thinkers. Need translation. Let's produce: 781:
You have Homer. You have the playwrights,
第一点是希腊人创造了一种全新的“人类”观念，
Aeschylus, Sophocles, and Euboides.
好吧！
And you have the philosophers, Plato and Aristotle.
接下来我们来看看主要的思想家。
And you have the philosophers, Plato and Aristotle. Alright.
第一个方面是希腊人创造了一种全新的“人类”观念，
So the Greeks created a new way of being a human.
希腊人创造了一个全新的“人类”观念，
Alright. Alright.
好的，先来看看希腊人！
Alright. Alright. Alright.
好的。好的。好的。
Alright. Alright. Alright. Alright. Alright. Alright.
好的，好的，好的，好的！
Alright. Alright. Alright. Alright.
好的，好的！
Alright. Alright.
...
Alright. Because
译文1
the point of listening to Homer was to enter Homer's world
译者翻译
and become Achilles or Odysseus.
并成为阿基里斯或奥德修斯。
And through this process, you became a different person.
通过这一步，变成了不同的个体。
And therefore, you learned empathy,
并且...
but you also expanded your imagination.
...
Okay? So that's what Homer did for the Greeks.
好的？所以这就是荷马为希腊所做的事。
Then you have Aeschylus, Sophrates, and Eupodes.
然后是有点儿…
And what they did that was different is,
2024-11-12 1/2?1..??…………
rather than think directly at the audience,
? 1..??..???………
they had the characters face each other in a dialogue, in a debate.
他们把角色安排成互相对话，进行辩论。
Okay? And by doing this,
...
what happens is you
在 生成 之 先 先 先...
create the capacity for perspective
and inner debate.
和内在
Right? Because before, you were part of...
the story.
翻译后...
Now you have to step back and judge the story.
现在 好 好 先 先 先…
There's a debate going on.
...
You have to switch perspectives in order to understand the characters.
你需要在此处...
And this creates the capacity for an inner monologue.
和这产生了内在的能力。
Okay? And a debate in you.
好的？】
And then you have Plato and Aristotle.
...
What Plato did that
was unique was he took all the dialogue in the play.
它独一无二，因他把全部对话搬到舞台上。
And he transported it onto the page.
But now, you're reading it by yourself.
但现在，你正自读它。
And you have the benefit of time.
再来，时间给你好处。”
Okay? And so,
好的？然后，这就产生了理性与思考的能力。
this creates a capacity for reason and reflection.
好的？然后呢，这就产生了理性与思考。”
Okay? You can sort of reason out if the words make sense to you.
好的？你可以先把单词拆开，去看它们的意思。”“把单词拆开后，单词本身的单词。”
You are no longer influenced by the crowd or the emotions of the actor.
“可是…………”
You can just look at the words themselves.
你可以先看单词本身。
And judge them on their own merit.
再来，单词本身再来。”
You also have the capacity now to reflect.
你现在也能回到单词本身。”
Meaning, you can go back to the words over and over the course of your lifetime.
意思是你可以在一生中反复回到单词本身。
To constantly reflect on their meaning and logic.
再来，单词本身。”
Okay? You understand?
再来…
So, when you add these three things together.
所以，当你把这三件事加在一起时。
Homer created the capacity for empathy and imagination.
荷马创作了同感与想象的能力。
The playwright created the capacity for inner debate and perspective.
剧作家创作了内在辩论与视角的能力。
The philosophers created the capacity for reason and reflection.
哲学家们创造了理想与思考的能力。
You now have a new human mind.
现在给你一个新的人类思维。
Okay? And when you study all of them.
好的，回到本身。”
This is what we call a liberal arts education.
这就是我们所说的自由艺术教育。
Alright? And guess what?
好，回到本身？
Our greatest thinkers came to us through the liberal arts.
我们的最优秀的古典文学…
Alright? Alright? Alright?
好的？好的？好的？
Alright? Alright?
好的？好的？
the greatest thinkers of the past 20 years,
好的，...??
they all, what was common about them is, they all read the Greeks.
他们都一样，什么是共同点就是他们都读了希腊的文字。
And that was just their education.
又是个别的……………??
Alright, so this is the first legacy of the Greeks.
先前……??
A new way of being and seeing.
一个新的存在与观照方式。
Okay, does that make sense? Second thing is,
OK? 这算是个别的??
now that you have this Greek world,
??
the Greeks need to establish a cohesive cultural identity.
希腊人需要建立统一的文化身份。
And they did that
他们做到了
by promoting a Greek education.
通过推广希腊教育。
Okay, but not only that, but
??
they had to bring in local people into this education.
...
So one major function of the Library of Alexandria
was to standardize and systemize Greek knowledge.
为了统一并系统化希腊知识。
And they did this by standardizing the text.
他们通过统一文本来完成此事。
Okay, so there are different texts that were written by Homer.
好的，...
The text of Homer that
...
we have today was developed by the people at the Library of Alexandria.
我们今天所拥有的，正是由亚历山大图书馆的人们所发展出来的。
Standardization. They also did something called commentaries.
标准化。它们还做了一个叫做“注释”。”
So commentaries are basically like teacher handbooks.
注释基本上是教师手册的样子。
They teach you how to teach this stuff.
它们给你们说了…
And they create like footnotes and
译文1
chapters and page numbers,
译文2
codices, indexes.
译文
Okay, so the point was to make Greek education
]? ?????????????????????????? ...?????? ...?????? ...??? ...??? ...??..?????? ...??..??? “………”……………………………………………………?……..??………………………?……..??………
available and accessible to anyone.
可用且可接触的…
All right, and what this means is, we in China now can actually read Homer,
翻译后...
Issylus, and Plato for ourselves.
}]
Even though we are not culturally Greek.
And that's the benefit of the pan -Hellenistic project.
...
All right. And
the third major benefit
第三个主要好处
is Greek knowledge meant a global development.
是希腓知识成了全球发展。
Revolution. And innovation, okay?
翻译1
And what I mean by that is, remember,
翻译2
Greek knowledge is being spread all around the world.
希腓知识正在全球传播。
And then they're interacting with powerful local cultures.
随后它们与当地强大文化相互作用。
And through the process of synchronization,
通过同步过程，新的知识形态正在形成。
new forms of knowledge are being created.
通过同步过程，新型知识形态正在生成。
Okay? So
好的？所以
the Greeks spread the knowledge to India.
希腓的知识在古希腓里传到古印度
And now it's interacting with local Indian philosophies.
现在它与当地印度哲学相互作用。
And religion, including new ideas.
宗教与新思想相互作用。
Right? So
好的？所以
the most famous synchronization
最 先前的同步化
is in the Levant.
...
Greek knowledge was being spread to the Jews.
Okay? And so when you put the Greeks and the Jews together,
...
you have a new idea that
would forever revolutionize human history.
...
And it's called Christianity. All right?
So Christianity would not have been possible if it
...
were not for the work of Aristotle.
未必为亚里士多德的工作。
Okay? All right.
好的？好吧。
So those are the three major legacies of the Greeks.
于是这就是希腊的三大遗产。
And so it is,
...
I think it's perfectly fair to say the Greeks were the most influential
and consequential civilization of all time.
...
They were certainly the most creative. No other civilization even comes close to their creativity.
他们确实是最具创造力的。没有其他文明能与之相提并论。
All right? Okay.
好吧？好的。
So that's it. Any questions?
于是就是这样。还有什么问题吗？
Okay. So…
好的，...
Okay. So we are finished with the Greeks.
Next class we start a new unit on Rome…
...
Roman history. All right?
罗马史。好吧？
So… Great.
好，...太好了。